#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/bijaybaniya (LinkedIn) bijaybaniya.com.np (Personal)

Top Skills
ASP.NET AJAX
ASP.NET
jQuery

#### Languages

English

Nepali (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional

Exam 480: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

#### Honors-Awards

Creative Employee of the month
Smart Employee of the month
The outstanding product ownership
1st at Open Programming
competition

Initiative and ownership Employee of the year

# Bijaya Baniya

Senior Software Engineer | Development Team Lead | ASP.NET CORE MVC full stack Engineer | Web Developer| API, Microservice ,Saas, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Python, MSSQL.Azure

Kathmandu

## Summary

As a software engineering leader with extensive experience in developing and delivering new and innovative SaaS Platform and CMS products, I have been influential in significantly increasing customer value across multiple platforms.

I have over 9+ years of experience in leading and mentoring crossfunctional, diverse teams that have gone on to be high-performing achieving significant results both individually and as a team. I know the mark of a great leader is one who is willing to continually invest in their team, which is why I make it a point to ensure there is always an emphasis on continuous improvement for continual success. Now studying data analysis and prediction using Al algorithms.

Skills: ASP.NET, C#.NET Core MVC, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Python, MSSQL, ElasticSearch, API, Microservices, AZURE

Some of my key achievements include:

# 8+ years of experience in leading and mentoring the team in ASP.NET technology

# Developed SaaS based site builder where users can get the websites on demand for different products with different themes. It includes dynamically deployment of products across multiple VM (Linux/Windows): hosting websites in IIS/NGINX, deploying database, managing mail server, managing scheduler services using APIs and Microservices.

# Organize stand up meetings as scrum master, help the team to meet the project deadlines.

# Developed open source .net CMS and CMF that can easily fulfill any organizational website need and even add their needed feature easily.

# Implemented design and template prediction of websites using Al algorithms and scrappers.

# Perform the CI-CD of products into testing, staging, and production server helping the team for quick test, review, demo as well as update the production products.

# Solution Development and Delivery: Analyze technical and functional design requirements; designs and codes superior technical solutions; identifies system deficiencies and recommends solutions.

#### My area of expertise:

- Strategic Team Leader
- System Analyst
- Specialised in CMS development
- Passionate to learn new everyday
- Focused on the smooth delivery of products
- Enthusiastic data scientist

I am interested in connecting with other like-minded professionals in my field. Feel free to contact me through this profile if you wish to connect.

# Experience

Xtrastaff
Development Team Lead
October 2021 - Present (10 months)
Kathmandu, Bāgmatī, Nepal

## Braindigit

9 years 7 months

Development Team Lead April 2015 - July 2021 (6 years 4 months) Kathmandu, Nepal

Senior Software Engineer January 2014 - April 2015 (1 year 4 months) Kathmandu, Nepal

Junior Software Engineer April 2012 - January 2014 (1 year 10 months) Kathmandhu, Nepal

#### Intern

January 2012 - April 2012 (4 months)

Kathmandu Nepal

# Education

Gandaki College of Engineering and Science Bachelor, Computer Software · (2007 - 2011)

Amarsingh Higher Secondary School +2, Science · (2005 - 2007)